THIS FILM IS BASED ON REAL EVENTS
-[tapping echoes]
-[dramatic music rises]
[flamenco music swells]
[grunts]
[sighs]
TO THE MAX
[intense tapping]
[man 1] I'm not convinced
anyone's gonna be interested.
-[interviewer] Why is that?
-Because what we do is too dangerous.
People see us as a bunch of lunatics
or idiots who are craving attention.
But I assure you, I'm neither.
I give lectures on this for a living.
I've been involved
with extreme sports since I was young.
BMX championships since I was 20.
I've done some crazy things,
but, uh… I'm not irresponsible.
I'm actually… quite responsible.
So… where do you think you want to start?
[man 2] With Chana.
He's the one who started it.
[thunder rumbles]
REINEBRINGEN, NORWAY
[majestic music playing]
[screaming]
[groaning]
-Oh!
-[man 2] Chana was pure energy.
A real force of nature.
[yelps]
[man 2] The kind who would go
to Norway for a solo jump.
Fuck! [groans]
[cries out]
[man 2] And walk two miles through
the mountains with a broken tibia.
Hey!
My leg is broken.
[straining]
-[fisherman] Are you okay?
-No!
My leg is broken.
I need help.
-Should we call a helicopter?
-Huh?
-What?
-Helicopter.
No. No helicopter. No.
Call an ambulance.
Please. Helicopter's too expensive.
I can't do it.
[sighs] There's no one like him.
That man's the one
who brought us together.
Darío, Carlos, and me.
And the two from Barcelona,
Álvaro and Santi.
One day we get a call and he says,
"I've been talking to the Catalans
who've been in the Pyrenees for months,
trying something called wingsuit flying."
"You guys want to check it out?"
It was around my birthday,
and what better way to celebrate
than trying something new for a change?
-[man 3] It's so thin.
-[Álvaro] It's nylon. Super light.
No, thanks, Álvaro.
I prefer the old-fashioned way.
[Álvaro] This doesn't even compare.
You get to fall for so much longer.
The wings inflate and you just glide.
-But then, how do you land with it?
-There's a chute. Here.
Except for the harness… is on the inside.
[plane engine whirring]
I say we give it a shot.
I thought you were nuts,
but now, that sounds brilliant.
-[engine starts]
-[both laugh]
[intense flamenco music playing]
[music intensifies]
-It's gonna blow your mind.
-[Chana] That's why we're here.
-[Álvaro] That's right!
-Okay.
-We're doing this.
-[laughing]
[Darío sighs]
Carlitos.
[wind whipping]
[screams]
Whoo-hoo!
[clucking]
[exclaims, laughs]
[laughs, shouts]
[screaming]
[Chana] Alvarito, here I come!
Time to fly.
[screams] Oh shit!
[laughing] Whoa!
-[Chana] Holy fuck!
-Whoa!
[laughing] Whoo!
[shouts, laughs]
Whoo!
[screams]
[grunting]
[laughs]
[Carlos screams]
-[man 2] Carlos, we're flying!
-[laughing]
[sighs]
-[Álvaro] Carlos! You like it?
-[Carlos] Hell yeah! Whoo-hoo!
[Álvaro] Let's go! [laughs]
[group exclaims]
[chuckling]
[Carlos shouts]
[uplifting music playing]
[Carlos] Holy shit!
[laughs] Yeah!
We fuckin' flew! Whoa!
[man 2 shouts, laughs]
Whoo! Whoo! Whoo!
God damn!
[laughing]
[raucous laughter]
[Darío] Whoo-hoo! [laughs]
-Yeah!
-[all cheering]
-[all exclaim]
-That was fuckin' awesome!
[excited chatter]
-[group] ♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
-[Carlos laughing]
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday, dear Carlos ♪
-♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
-[Carlos] Oh.
[all cheer]
-[Darío] Make a wish, buddy.
-[Chana] A good one!
-[Álvaro] Way to go!
-[laughter and applause]
-[Darío] Happy birthday.
-[Álvaro] Let's hope it comes true!
Trust me, you're gonna stall
if you bank too hard.
-Not if you control your speed.
-How do you know what that is?
Look at this guy. He's done it one time,
and he's already an expert.
[man 2] So annoying.
Okay, okay, okay, I have a few things
to say before I'm too drunk.
Uh, Carlitos, this is the age
you'll have your first existential crisis.
Don't panic, and remember this.
Whenever well-meaning idiots
say only rich guys
can afford extreme sports,
I tell them about our friend Carlos.
Who's always lived day to day
and free as the wind.
-Took a page out of your book, Dad.
-You traitor. I do own three restaurants.
They're nothing fancy.
I don't make millions. They're all right.
Yeah. I'll give you that.
-Not quite as much as Armando's place.
-No. My mother's.
Of course,
so that leaves Darío's cookbooks.
-[group laughs]
-Want a signed one?
[Chana] Our dear little Carlos
has made a living climbing mountains!
When I met this kid, uh, five years ago,
I was beyond fuckin' jealous!
-No shit.
-And then I told myself…
Just wait and see how long this upstart
lasts with his cute little backpack on,
beggin' for sponsors.
Let him want to save for a down payment
and start paying a mortgage.
No, thanks. I like renting, Chana.
And he says it so casual.
Guy is my goddamn hero.
You crack 26,000 in the Himalayas,
then Yosemite to conquer El Capitan,
and you go off to Greenland.
With that same little backpack,
and you never have to punch in!
-[Armando] Genius!
-[group laughs]
-Hey, I'm turning 35, not 50, man.
-Yeah, that's it, kid.
[Chana] If you didn't understand
what I'm trying to say, it's this.
Stay the course, brother.
Don't you ever change.
And don't you dare get nominated
for Employee of the Month.
-[group laughs]
-I love it.
-I love you. [laughs]
-So good.
-Got it? Yeah?
-Only Chana.
[Chana] I'm telling you this, there will
come a time when the pressure is intense.
Doesn't matter who you are.
It's gonna come.
You have to resist, Carlos.
For yourself and for all of us.
You gotta hold on to that spark
and always be yourself.
Stay strong and don't give in, brother.
The world needs our Carlos.
It needs the kid and whatever's
in his silly little backpack. I mean it.
[Carlos] What fascinates me the most
about the Trango massif
is that it rises
over a ridge of pure granite.
It's between two glaciers,
the Trango to the west,
and the Dunge to the east.
This entire range is incredible.
But the one that really stands out
to me is… the Nameless Tower.
The weather there can be treacherous.
I tried climbing it a few years ago,
and… a storm forced us to give up.
We were only about 2,000 feet
from the summit.
-[man] How high is it?
-[Carlos] Just over 20,400 feet.
It has nine routes, with the first one
established in 1976 by Joe Brown.
And in my humble opinion,
the most impressive route is the--
[woman] The Slovenian.
Uh, that's right.
Um, it's on the southwest face
and has the cleanest cracks for climbing.
And some fixed ropes, which is huge.
Does the record still belong to Singleman?
Yeah, but it was Singleman and Feteris.
Both BASE jumpers. Australians.
They did a jump from 19,537.4.
The highest to date.
And one of the highest vertical drops
in the world.
[indistinct chatter]
NAMELESS TOWER
Hi, Carlos.
Do you have a few minutes to talk?
I'm Myriam Montañana.
-Is this what you do?
-I'm a biologist.
But I love everything about climbing,
so your lecture caught my attention.
-Ah.
-Do you have a moment?
-Well, I--
-Look, I'm not a groupie, okay?
-I have a proposal.
-A proposal?
An expedition to beat the record.
BASE jumping off the Trango tower.
It's all in here.
Permits and costs, budget,
potential sponsors, required resources,
and the filmmakers
who want access to the expedition.
In exchange for full funding.
They want a team of five
to ensure interaction.
There aren't five guys who can climb
Nameless and then jump off it.
Not everyone has to jump.
I'm certainly not planning to.
You?
If you tell me it's guys only,
it won't go well.
No. It's not about that.
This mountain's not for amateurs.
So, if this is for show,
then this is not where--
I'm not an amateur. It's not a show.
I've been climbing since I was a teenager.
I've gone to the Sierra de Madrid,
the Picos, the Gredos,
I've got sixth- and seventh-grade routes
under my belt--
-How old are you?
-I've done the Alps as well.
No offense, but the Trango
is on another level.
Why don't I prove it?
[scoffs]
EMERGENCY EXIT
[Carlos] The owner's a friend,
and I can come whenever I want.
The difficulty ranges from six-,
seven-, to eight-grade routes.
But we'll start with something easy.
You bring all the girls here
to impress them?
[scoffs] You're the first.
[chuckles]
Honest. [scoffs]
[intense music playing]
So the guy who would produce the movie
is going out with a friend of yours?
Yes. Right now he caters to idiots.
But he's a total sports nut, so, I said,
"Why don't you do something
more like National Geographic?"
-Huh. Pretty forward.
-Yeah.
[grunts]
-Shy and patient aren't really my thing.
-Yeah, I noticed.
I'm just surprised you didn't choose
another profession.
I mean, eight hours a day,
peering through a microscope?
And what am I doing now? [scoffs]
-[grunts, panting]
-[tense music playing]
[strains]
[Carlos] Watch it. Stay focused.
Okay, there's a good foothold
just over to the left.
-It's all good. [sighs]
-Use that.
It's all good.
[panting]
[Carlos] You're heading to an 8a.
I know that.
[Carlos] Amazing!
[tense music subsides]
If your idea was to make me back down,
you'll need a bigger wall.
[both laugh]
I said those things?
No, no, no, no.
I didn't challenge him. Impossible.
[Carlos laughs] Yes, she did.
While she was still up there.
So, of course, I decided,
"If this girl needs a bigger wall,
I'm gonna show her what that is."
If a helicopter drops me off
at the top, sure. Otherwise, no.
I'll teach you how to climb at this level.
You can't pass this up, man.
-You know what I think?
-What?
You are going above and beyond
to get this Myriam to sleep with you.
-Come on. Please, it's not like that.
-Oh, no?
How often have you heard me say I want
to go back to conquer this thing?
A lot. And you think it's a good idea.
So, we should follow?
-We have a sponsor.
-It's got nothing to do with that.
It's what Armando
and Darío are going through.
Okay, what is it?
For Armando, it's his brother renovating
the restaurant.
And Darío's getting divorced.
I know, but we wouldn't be going tomorrow.
We're looking more
in like six months at the earliest.
Did you tell the TV crew?
-No, not yet, but I will. Eventually.
-Oh?
We could set a new world record.
If we don't do it,
someone else is gonna get it.
You're the heart of the group.
If you're in, they're all in.
[energetic flamenco tapping]
[shouting]
[singing in Spanish]
[Armando] My dad opened the Corral
in the '50s.
It's a legendary flamenco place
that's hosted tons of famous people,
like Dominguín, Sinatra, Brando,
Tom Jones, Ali, and Japanese royalty.
It's also famous for being
where the Shah of Iran met his third wife,
Farah Diba.
It's where the four of us
would plan our expeditions.
So, when Carlos asked me to get
the boys together there,
I knew… it was big.
I just didn't know how big.
[Carlos] The Aussies jumped
from just over 19,000 feet,
but that's almost 1,000 feet
below Trango's summit.
It's three days of climbing.
Don't think about the climb,
think about the record.
The drop is over 6,000 feet,
for fuck's sake.
-Chana's up for it. Right?
-[sighs]
I'm in. Mm.
It's mostly to get my name
in the books, I won't lie.
[laughs]
If we take that girl
with us, then we can't--
-It's Myriam.
-Myriam.
[Chana laughs]
I was going to say that
we can't all jump and leave her alone.
Someone has to come down with her.
Carlitos… [laughs]
[chuckles] Maybe we get
a Sherpa to help us out.
So, we get Myriam a Sherpa?
She's an excellent climber.
Better than you guys.
-I've seen her on the wall.
-But an indoor wall's no comparison.
She'll train like the rest of us.
-[Chana] Okay.
-What do you think?
[Darío] I get wanting to climb Nameless.
But just beating a 20-year-old record
by such a small fraction is nothing.
In my opinion.
What do you mean?
We need to go there for something bigger…
[inhales sharply] …more radical.
Define "radical."
[takes a deep breath]
In wingsuits.
[scoffs] Such a show-off.
-Like always.
-[Darío] We might even win an Oscar.
You want another boring documentary
or something legendary?
Okay, is it possible to use wingsuits
at that altitude?
-You can. I know it's been done at 16,000.
-Mm.
-But those guys are wingsuit experts.
-So, how do we get there?
By logging 50 more jumps from a plane,
at a minimum.
-Plane's not a problem.
-But that only gets you hours.
You'll need a balloon to measure
the altitude margin. 1,900…
16,000…
[Chana exclaims]
[Álvaro] 13,000…
[both scream]
-[Álvaro] A thousand…
-Ready. Set. Go!
What are you planning, Carlos?
I want to do Nameless. In Pakistan.
Pretty sure it's over 16,000.
Just over 20,000. You think it's doable?
He did. But I started
to hate that damn hot air balloon.
We did it for three weeks.
Because the wings are something else.
When you're wearing them…
you're really flying.
[inspiring music playing]
[sighs]
[Chana] Hey! [laughing]
[group cheering and laughing]
[grunts]
It's too cool.
Whoa!
-Whoo!
-[Darío] I'm saying we step it up.
-You good?
-[Darío] BASE jumping from record heights.
I say we start training in the Pyrenees.
I have a better idea.
Mallos de Riglos.
There's an 800-foot vertical wall.
-Really?
-Yeah. It's only four hours away.
-So it's easy.
-[laughs]
I'm down to go, man.
We can do it this weekend.
You guys go, and I'll catch the next one.
I have an exhibition jump
at a festival in Toledo this weekend.
-I can't go.
-Carlos?
-I can't either. I've got something.
-What kind of something?
-Just training.
-On your own?
[scoffs] On his own if she cancels.
He didn't say he was training
with a suit on.
-You guys are assholes.
-[group laughing]
[Darío] Yeah.
[intense music rises]
The first 150 feet or so are easy.
They're maybe a five or six.
-Then it's about seven towards the top.
-Do we take turns?
No, I'll be belaying you while I go.
-So, who's belaying you?
-I have my chute in here.
-What?
-I've freebased this route before.
-You're going unattached?
-Piece of cake.
You trying to impress me?
So, you coming or not?
[tense music continues]
[Carlos grunts]
Final section!
Easy.
You got it.
[music grows uplifting]
[shouts]
[Carlos] Good job.
[uplifting music fades]
So, did I pass?
[both chuckle]
You don't pass
unless you get back to base camp alive.
You'll be climbing back down,
not flying like us.
Let me get this straight,
your big concern
is whether I can get back down?
Nameless is super technical.
I bet I make it to the car before you.
My boots versus your chute.
Seriously?
The car is parked… to the west.
The wind's against you.
-I have the advantage.
-[scoffs]
Keep dreaming.
-[giggles]
-Hold on! Wait! But what about my banana?
[energetic music playing]
-[chute whooshes]
-[panting]
[energetic music fades]
[both laughing]
You don't wanna jump?
It's not my thing.
How do you know?
I'm a land mammal. I don't want to fly.
Climbing wasn't my thing
until someone got me to try it.
Who was that?
-He was a friend of the family.
-Mm.
I was a real pain in the ass.
My grades sucked.
So did my attitude,
and… he took me out one weekend
to give my mom a break,
and he basically forced me
to climb for two days.
-You got hooked?
-Mm-hmm.
Halfway up the first wall,
I felt like a god.
It's that cocktail of adrenaline
and endorphins you didn't know you needed.
Yeah, but that's not all it was.
Everything fell into place.
The climbing made me realize
that the reason I'd been acting that way
was because I lacked vision.
And when I got to the top,
it was just like, "This is your life."
"Your calling."
[chuckles]
I'm sure you'd love to fly.
[crowd cheering]
[announcer on PA]
…for their impressive display.
And keep that applause coming
to cheer on our next guests,
who are preparing to wow you!
[crowd cheers]
Go get 'em, Dad!
[announcer] And, of course, a parachute.
They'll be performing tricky maneuvers
that require not only…
[engine roars]
Let's let them know
we look forward to the show.
And keep an eye out for the colored smoke
that's gonna let you follow them
through the sky.
[sighs]
-Let's go, boys.
-Enjoy.
Let's go.
[suspenseful music rises]
Okay?
-Off we go. Can't wait to get down there.
-[man] Let's go.
Yeah. [exclaims]
[music ends]
[cell phone ringing]
[tense music playing]
Yeah?
The… the connection's bad.
Armando, I'm gonna call you back.
I can barely hear you.
Yeah. You there?
Man, I'll try again.
-I'll call you back from somewhere else.
-What is it?
-Um, I'm not sure, but I think it's bad.
-How bad?
[tense music swells]
[brakes screech]
Daddy?!
[sirens approaching]
[engine revving]
[cell phone rings]
-Who is it?
-It's Darío.
-Put it on speaker.
-[phone beeps]
Darío!
-Darío?
-[Darío] Where are you?
On my way home.
What's going on? Armando called too.
It was a downplane.
Goddamn. Is he still with us?
They're treating him on the runway.
But it's not looking too good. [sighs]
Carlos?
I'm about an hour out,
and I can get you on the way.
-[distorted] Carlos?
-Darío?
[static crackles]
No network connection.
-[sighs]
-[Carlos] Fucking hell.
-[engine revs]
-[Carlos] Shit!
[indistinct radio chatter]
[paramedic] One, two, three, four.
-[crying softly]
-[mournful music rises]
[Carlos, muffled] Okay.
Where was this?
Yeah, I'll be there.
[melancholic flamenco music rises]
[music fades]
It was Chana's time.
The margin was there.
It was a simple demonstration jump.
-He'd done plenty of them.
-[Armando] It was very low risk.
The only difference… was the wings.
Part of doing what we do is knowing
that bad things happen regardless.
You just have to accept that.
[bells tolling]
[trowel scraping]
[slow, mournful music playing]
[worker 1] I think we're ready now, okay?
Hand me the stone.
[mourners crying]
Okay.
-[worker 2 grunts]
-[worker 1] We got it.
-[worker 2] You good?
-[sighs]
-[worker 1] Here we go.
-[indistinct chatter]
Thanks.
-[speaking indistinctly]
-I'm here.
[sighs] We gotta check in on her.
She's still gonna jump
at Lleida next week.
[Carlos] Good.
If she stops, she'll get too scared.
[indistinct chatter]
So awful seeing your dad die like that.
No, it's not.
Watching your dad wither away
after fighting cancer two years is awful.
He only knew he was gonna die for, what?
Maybe… a few seconds?
[somber music fades]
Eh? Five seconds of his entire existence?
With the life he led?
[chuckles sadly]
[chuckles]
[sniffles]
[announcer speaking indistinctly]
[jumpers shouting]
[footsteps approach]
[announcer speaking indistinctly]
You really want to watch that?
[Armando sighs]
Right now, I mean?
Well, it's either this
or drink until I pass out.
Chamomile does the same thing.
-If Chana were here, he wouldn't…
-Yeah.
-But he's not here.
-[sighs]
He would be mad at us
if we threw in the towel.
I don't want you to, either.
You do want something, though?
I thought we could try to get away.
Drive down to Portugal,
go surfing, forget a little.
The only problem with that…
is I'm not looking to forget
all the good times we had.
Or the ones to come.
[video playing]
[jumpers exclaiming]
[laughter echoing]
[echoes fade]
[horns honking in distance]
[Armando] Come on, people like
that the Corral is traditional.
[Juanma] I know,
but it's not like it's never changed.
We're not the same as ten
or 20 years ago. We evolve.
Juan Manuel, we didn't get the cecina?
You remember, Mom?
I told you it's coming later.
What were you discussing?
I don't agree with any of the changes
my brother wants to make.
What don't you agree with?
This is progress.
-Madrid's changing, so why shouldn't we?
-Sous-vide cooking's not progress.
We won't know unless we try,
so we're trying.
All you've ever done is experiment.
And we've always been behind you.
With the BMX and the BASE jumping
and now this crazy trip to Pakistan.
Pakistan?
-After what happened to Chana?
-Mom, we don't even have a date for it.
Then there's absolutely no reason
you can't help your brother.
It's a big job. He needs you.
-[scoffs]
-Wait. The Corral is an institution.
[interviewer] What did you think
about the renovation plans?
[sighs, scoffs]
I thought the entire project
was ridiculous.
But when push comes to shove,
ya gotta choose your family.
[interviewer] So, you canceled Pakistan?
No.
[epic music playing]
[birds calling]
[intense flamenco beat rises]
[echoing] Ready? Set. Jump!
[wind whipping]
[screams]
[both laugh]
[music fades]
[Darío] I never cheated on my wife.
What are you talking about, man?
You attract women like flies.
So? It's one thing to flirt a little,
have a little fun. It's good for the ego.
-You hearing this?
-It doesn't mean anything.
I had plenty of hot,
sexy girlfriends, believe me.
But with her, it was different.
It was so much more.
It was fucking solid.
We had kids together.
Hand me the yogurt, would you?
You're using Greek yogurt?
-Who's the chef here?
-You are.
Then all of a sudden,
she blindsides me, says we're done.
Just says it's her, not me,
like we're in fucking high school.
-You sure it wasn't your cooking?
-[group laughs]
-So, extra pepper for you?
-[Álvaro] Oh, no, Chef. Not the pepper.
Bastard.
I have a question.
What's your opinion on sous-vide cooking?
Iris, we're not here to talk about work.
He's cooking for us right now.
I want to hear what he has to say.
If it's about updating your menu,
I agree with your brother.
Your menu has to evolve, or you're done.
So, why do you complain
about having to do it?
This is different.
You're a family institution
that's completely immune to failure.
I think you should hire a Basque chef.
A Basque chef for a tablao?
Are you serious?
I've got a few to recommend.
Your girlfriend's from Bilbao.
Does she know anyone?
-Oh, that's over. Didn't work out.
-Why not?
Oh, I took her to Switzerland
to watch me jump, and… [sighs]
-Freaked her right out.
-You forgot to take it slow, didn't you?
-Where did you take her?
-[Álvaro] This place called "the Crack."
[Armando] The Crack?
What the hell is the Crack?
It's a sort of canyon in the Alps.
Oh. Let me show you the video.
You got that sound in your voice.
I gotta see this.
[Álvaro] You jump from the top of a ridge
then head for the canyon.
You end up flying six feet from the edge.
Check it out.
-Here it is. Watch this.
-[Armando] Jesus Christ!
[Darío] That's the Crack?
-[Álvaro] Yeah, you drop right into it.
-[Darío] No wonder she left.
[laughing]
I've got a hard-on
just watching it though, man.
I'm heading over again in about a month.
You in?
[Darío laughing] What do you think?
I guess she didn't get
the same rush as you did.
[sighs] Who really does?
-Try dating a climber.
-You know this stuff's not for everyone.
-Only because they haven't tried it yet.
-[Darío scoffs]
-Or maybe they just want a normal life.
-[Myriam] Normal?
-With kids and a dog. Right?
-Mm.
Why would that stop you? Darío has kids.
-[Armando] He's past his prime, though.
-Hey!
-[laughs]
-It's hard to find that balance.
-I plan to have a family and still climb.
-Mm. [sighs]
Just wait a few years.
-[Myriam] Are you coming to Pakistan?
-[Iris] I don't know yet.
My work is a little stingy
with vacation days.
But I'd love to go.
Plus, I'm a better climber than Armando.
-[Myriam chuckles]
-[Iris] He'd say the same thing.
[Myriam] I know you can climb.
[both laugh]
What I said earlier about wanting
a normal life, I didn't mean for you.
-I'm used to it. I get that all the time.
-I do want kids, and a dog.
-But not Armando?
-Yes, he does. Definitely.
-I'm the one that keeps putting it off.
-For your career?
-[Iris] For him to stop jumping.
-Ah.
Right.
Why don't you jump?
[sighs]
When I took the training course,
they made us write a letter
to our loved ones
in case something went wrong
with our parachutes or something.
And… [sighs]
…I couldn't do it.
-So, I quit.
-I get it.
-You want a drink?
-[scoffs] At least one.
[Iris] I'm more into surfing, climbing,
trekking through the desert or the Arctic.
-Stuff like that.
-[both laugh]
Most of my friends
and colleagues work 9:00 to 5:00
and go to the mall on weekends,
like everybody else.
They must be jealous.
I wish. Most of my friends
think I'm nuts.
Only my mother gets it
'cause she's crazier than I am.
Why do they think you're nuts?
Because… I fell in love with a guy
who puts his life at risk as a hobby.
I don't see it like that.
You say that now, but it catches up.
There's more injuries than deaths, though.
Ever heard of the Fatality List?
Mm… no.
They put together a list
of those who have died BASE jumping
throughout the entire world.
It went up by 42 just last year.
[somber music playing]
That's just the way it is.
And I accept it.
My sister doesn't get it.
She says I'm too generous. [chuckles]
What do you tell her?
I tell her I'm happy.
She believes it?
Yes, she does.
[sighs]
[somber music intensifies]
-This is nuts.
-We got out of the plane.
We're glued to each other.
Trying to figure out where to put
my hands. I say, "Make some space."
But he's not doing anything but laughing.
These two, dropping like flies. [laughs]
-Only two morons like you.
-[Álvaro] We could've died.
[Carlos] Out of thin air, huh?
[Myriam] That time in Riglos was magical.
Not only because of the jumps
and the climbing,
but everything that went with it.
They'd known each other for four years,
but I was the new one.
The rookie.
I felt so privileged.
I saw… what bonded them.
The chemistry.
And what it meant to be part of a group.
It was their refuge.
It was their home.
And they like to celebrate too.
[interviewer] Celebrate what?
Mm, being alive.
-Hey! Hey!
-Take it off!
[all cheering]
["Supersubmarina" playing]
-Let's go!
-Oh my God!
You got lucky!
[Armando] Let's see it.
Four aces.
[group groans]
-[cheering]
-[uplifting Spanish rock music continues]
[energetic rock music fades]
-[hammers banging]
-[Iris] Holy cow!
-This is nothing.
-Did you call Darío's friend yet?
Yeah, but when I told him
it was for a flamenco tablao,
he thought it was a prank.
Does that mean he's not interested?
I don't know. He hung up. We'll see.
[Iris] It's stressing you out, isn't it?
They're just getting started.
And look at it.
And you should see my brother's ideas
for the kitchen.
Won't the chef decide the menu?
Juan Manuel's got so many ideas.
He wants to mousse and braise and liquify.
-It'll be a lab, not a restaurant.
-[chuckles]
-Mm. Darío called earlier.
-He did?
To tell me that if I really want
ultimate success, start our own franchise.
It pays a lot more than Michelin stars.
Mm-hmm. Is that what you want?
[phone ringing]
-My God.
-Hello?
No, it's the noise from the construction.
Say that again?
Jesus.
I was blindsided.
We talked not that long ago,
and he was so excited
about sending a team with us to Pakistan.
But now he doesn't want to. [sighs]
No money, no Nameless.
[Darío] Fuckin' asshole.
-This is all my fault.
-You didn't pull out.
My guy did.
I convinced you, you went to these guys--
No. You didn't.
I've been wanting to go for ages.
And we're doing it.
The documentary's nothing. Fuck that guy.
You want more coffee?
I need some more. [sighs]
She can hardly function.
She feels terrible.
What's our next move, then?
-[Carlos] Look for options.
-Options, huh?
-Like what?
-You mean start from scratch, Carlos?
-Christ.
-I don't know.
Why don't we go for a jump in Riglos
and forget about all this shit?
Yeah, I'd love to, but we gotta start
making phone calls now, all of us.
I've got my kids this weekend. I can't.
-Go with Iris.
-She's busy.
Álvaro? He could show you that canyon
he was talking about.
[ominous flamenco music rises]
[music intensifies]
LAUTERBRUNNEN, SWITZERLAND
[Álvaro] The height is about 2,100 feet.
You stabilize then accelerate.
You want to go over the plain
and head towards the entrance
by the trees you see on the right.
That's where you enter the Crack.
-[Armando] And you fly through it?
-That's the whole point.
-[Armando] Fuck. [laughs]
-Best seven seconds of your life in there.
When you're out,
then you let the parachute do the work.
Now I understand why the Basque girlfriend
dumped you.
[both laugh]
They canceled it?
And the funding went with it?
Apparently, we're too boring. For a film.
-Too boring?
-Yeah.
So, wingsuits are boring now?
Flying over 100 miles per hour
is too boring too?
-It doesn't help we don't post about it.
-That's all we need.
I can't stand those people who go halfway
around the world just for a selfie.
To climb a tower
or hang off a fucking train.
Yeah, or eat scorpions.
Then there's parkour,
doing flips off the roof.
I can't watch those guys.
It doesn't make sense to do that.
[huffs]
Just imagine what they would say
if we posted, though.
-[chuckles]
-I mean it. It's… It's insane.
[both laugh]
[Álvaro chuckles softly]
I needed this, though.
I can tell.
Don't let it be a habit.
You start to use jumping
as an easy fix, then…
then the beast will want its due.
-The beast?
-[foreboding music rises]
[thunder rumbles in distance]
[foreboding music intensifies]
[eagle crying]
[wind whistling]
Ready. Set.
Go!
[wind whistling]
[intense music playing]
Over there.
[Álvaro shouting] Wow!
[yells]
[uplifting music rises]
[both exclaiming]
[shouts, laughs]
Yeah!
-Crazy, huh?
-[laughing] Unbelievable! Holy shit!
[both laugh and exclaim]
Terrifying, isn't it?
It's fucked. I missed smacking
those trees by inches.
-You think up there, you are toast.
-The Crack! [laughing]
-[sighs]
-[exclaims, laughs]
-[Armando] Incredible.
-[gentle music playing]
[Álvaro] We all went to Angel Falls
in Venezuela a few years ago.
-Nice.
-[Álvaro] Five days of trekking.
Three nights on top of the falls.
Nonstop rain.
It was wet 24 hours straight,
the whole time we went there.
I've never seen anything like it.
[conversation continues indistinctly]
[Álvaro] I first tried the wingsuit
in the Pyrenees.
Then I got my buddies to try.
They're all hooked.
Whoever invented these things
was a freaking genius.
[Armando] We were supposed
to leave the next morning.
Álvaro had to get home to Barcelona,
so we needed an early start.
[interviewer] But you changed your plans?
[gentle music fades]
[sighs]
[sniffles] It was so beautiful,
we couldn't resist jumping one more time.
[uneasy music rises]
[wind howling]
[man 1] Hey!
Are you doing the Crack again? [grunts]
I can't imagine doing this that hung over,
can you?
We'll scare 'em sober.
This ain't no joke. [chuckles]
I'll head to the right this time.
I'm gonna fly like the wind.
So, no Crack?
Yesterday was so good.
I wanna remember the magic.
-[sighs]
-[man 1] Enjoy the flight, boys.
-Ready, set, go.
-[man 1] See you at the bottom!
[epic music playing]
[chute whooshes]
[exhales]
[cowbells ringing]
[group cheering]
I knew it'd be that fucking fantastic!
Holy shit! [exclaims]
-That was insane!
-[man 2] I told you it was crazy.
-[man 1] I was close to the rocks, man.
-[both laughing]
-[Armando] Hey!
-[man 1 exclaims]
-Hey! Have you seen my friend?
-Huh?
-My friend.
-What?
-Is he not here?
-No.
I saw he was a bit unstable
near the canyon.
-[Armando] What?
-Uh…
Yeah, he was a little wobbly
entering the Crack.
-He was flying a little weird.
-Yeah.
[Armando] Álvaro!
[ominous music rises]
Álvaro!
-Álvaro!
-[man 2] Hey!
Over here! He's here!
I found him!
He's here.
[interviewer] And what do you remember?
Most of what I remember is bits
and pieces.
I was in shock.
[unsettling rumbling]
No, I think it's better if you stay there.
You shouldn't look.
[mournful music rises]
[quietly] No.
[sighs]
[Myriam] That's when I realized
that the Fatality List
wasn't something that happened to others.
It's real.
[Carlos sighs] Álvaro's accident
got a lot of press.
It was everywhere.
They talked about our wingsuits.
Called us a bunch of yahoos.
And they tried to make an example of him.
-[interviewer] How, exactly?
-By saying, "I told you so." That's how.
[Carlos] I've been losing friends
since I was 20.
You never get used to it.
And you shouldn't.
You take the hit and keep living.
[interviewer] And the fear?
You better be scared.
It's a problem if you're not.
'Cause without fear…
I remember going to Carlos
to tell him I had to take a break.
I had no idea if I would need, uh,
two months, two weeks, two days, or, uh…
I wasn't backing out of the trip
to Pakistan, but I… couldn't fly.
-[interviewer] How'd he take it?
-[Carlos] I told him I understood.
To take as long as he needed.
I would work on the funding.
And he and Darío
would be kept in the loop.
[interviewer] Darío wanted a break too?
[chuckles] No. Darío didn't take breaks.
-[Myriam] Darío was a hurricane.
-[hopeful music rises]
What would demolish others
only made him stronger.
[sighs] I'm sorry,
but is this some kind of joke?
That's what it tastes like.
You have no idea
how to make vichyssoise, do you?!
[Armando] Darío was brutally honest.
But inside, he was a big softie.
The most kid-friendly guy I ever met.
-[all] Popcorn!
-Yes!
[Armando] When he and his wife split up,
he moved in with his sister
to be closer to her and her girls.
This might be the best batch of spaghetti
I've ever cooked.
-Who wants some?
-I do. I want some.
[Armando] He loved their laughter.
…three, four, five, six, seven, eight!
[laughing] Oh no!
Oh, you little weasel!
Mm. I just needed one more!
[music fades]
He was unique.
[somber piano music playing]
He didn't know how… to take a break.
Or want to.
[Darío] I don't have to be ashamed
of the way I live.
I'm not hurting anyone, am I?
[camera shutter clicking]
[Darío] Do I like to travel? Yes, I do.
Do I like to have a good time?
As much as I can.
Do I practice extreme sports?
-Yes.
-[audience laughs]
If someone asked me to choose,
cooking and BASE jumping,
I don't think I could
because I love them equally.
But more importantly,
they both hold me by the jewels.
And both come with their own risks
because they're both high pressure.
-The pressure in the kitchen--
-Cooking can't kill you.
-[woman] She's right.
-Not literally, I mean.
Hm. Bernard Loiseau. You know who that is?
One of the best chefs in the world.
He lost one star
and put a bullet in his head.
That's real pressure.
Mind you, to relax,
I could try bocce or lawn bowling
or something like that, but…
-[audience laughs]
-But it's not my kind of thing.
Do you care if people judge you?
[Darío] Do you think I don't know
what people say about extreme sports?
You think we must be crazy,
or we have a screw loose,
or worst of all, that somehow
we don't value our time on this earth.
That we don't value being alive.
Which is just crazy.
Because you'll never feel more alive
than when… you're ready to jump.
-It's a bit like heroin, isn't it?
-[audience murmurs]
If you want to escape,
by all means, do drugs.
But I've never been more present
than up there.
So alive.
[audience applauds]
We'll invite one of those producers
and sweet-talk him into it.
-He'll sponsor the whole thing.
-Yeah? How?
We invite him to join us at The Corral.
Have Armando bring us his best wine,
and when the guy's had three glasses,
we put the contract under his nose.
-And that's that.
-Sure. Very professional.
It'd be much easier to get a loan.
It's not even that much money.
-It's about 6,000 each, right?
-Sorry, but that's just not how it works.
-Banks loan money all the time.
-You've never done this.
[huffs] Why won't it work?
You can't walk in and tell the guy,
"Give me money to go to the Himalayas."
-It doesn't work that way.
-The wind's picking up! Get a move on!
-[Myriam] I'm out of breath already.
-[Carlos] Wait till you see the jump.
[wind whistling]
[panting]
[sighs]
Whoa. [exclaims, chuckles]
Look at this thing.
[Carlos] The air's heavy.
Nah…
Anyway, we're not wearing our suits.
I think it's a bit unstable.
And the currents are tricky.
You think it won't be worse
on top of Trango?
I'm not walking
all the way back down, brother.
[Carlos] Wait, wait. I'll go first.
-You sure?
-[Carlos] Yeah.
-Carlos.
-I've been here more.
Carlos…
You got it. It's all good.
[huffs]
I'll be fine.
-See you down there, okay?
-Hey.
-Enjoy the flight.
-Yeah.
You call it.
[exhales]
Ready! Set!
-Go!
-[intense music playing]
[Darío] Open… open.
[exhales]
Nice.
[wind blowing]
[ominous music playing]
-[Darío] Oh shit.
-[Myriam] What's wrong?
[Darío] The fucking wind's behind him.
-It'll push him against the rocks.
-[Myriam] Jesus.
-Get outta there. Get the fuck out.
-[Myriam gasps]
-[inhales sharply]
-[Darío] God damn it.
Carlos!
Can you hear us?!
Are you okay?
Are you okay?!
[music intensifies]
[panting]
Carlos?
Carlos!
Oh, Jesus! Carlos!
Can you hear me?
-You're okay. Don't move, all right?
-Yeah, yeah.
Oh, fuck, that was close.
Stay still.
[groans]
-Where's Myriam?
-She's coming.
-Just relax. [sighs]
-[groans weakly]
[busy chatter]
[Armando] This way.
There she is.
How is he?
Broken septum.
They're still working on him.
They said his helmet is what saved him.
What happened?
[Myriam sighs]
-A broken septum's no big deal.
-Mm.
These things happen
all the time in football.
I know.
[woman on PA] Doctor Salazar
to the birthing center. Doctor Salazar.
[Myriam sighs]
You know what?
This morning I totally chickened out.
I was gonna tell Carlos
we should move in together.
[Iris] Really?
We're going on eight months.
But somehow, I couldn't.
I don't know if it was…
[Iris] Self-preservation?
[Myriam sighs] Mm.
I've always been the intrepid one
in my family.
The one to jump right into things.
But lately, I've been wondering…
what else is there?
Have you ever gone
to the Orsay Museum in Paris?
[Myriam] Hm?
Armando and I went there one weekend.
We toured with a guide who was telling us
about the Renoir, Manet, and Degas.
-Mm.
-Then in this one room…
He had us stop
in front of his favorite work.
It was of a boy looking out a window.
The light reflecting
onto his face was… gorgeous.
While we were looking at it,
the guide said something
about beauty that floored both of us.
-It floored you?
-Yes.
He told us, "Beauty only shows itself
when the person admiring
the painting disappears."
True beauty emerges when the impact of
the work is so strong nothing else exists.
-Hmm.
-It's like it creates its own world.
As soon as he said that, I turned around
to see what Armando thought
about what he'd just heard.
And with a huge smile he says,
"Iris, he just described
what flying feels like."
"I disappear. I don't exist."
[Myriam sighs]
You know what we did after that?
We ran to our hotel
and screwed so hard we broke the bed.
-[both laugh]
-It was nuts.
I chose him.
[reflective music playing]
So, those times I've asked myself
what else is there,
I didn't have an answer.
Because it doesn't matter.
[Myriam sighs]
[sighs]
[somber music continues]
[door closes]
Darío, baby, his nose is gonna be fine.
[reflective music fades]
The nose is nothing, Silka.
Par for the course.
-It's the concussion I feel bad about.
-Oh?
No jumps for at least six months.
So?
The guy almost died because of me.
I'm supposed to accept you were scared
for Carlos,
but when we worry about you,
we're breaking your balls? That's fucked.
-Don't start.
-Don't start what?
-Going into mom mode.
-Jesus! [laughs]
Please. Don't judge me.
You never have before.
Not to your face.
-Well, thanks for letting me pretend.
-Mm. [sighs]
We've all had to pretend.
I don't know if you realize
what pretending cost your family.
I didn't ask for anything.
My only vice is I like the rush.
I'm not hurting anyone
or being an asshole.
I know. And I've always defended you.
But you have kids who depend on you now.
And they love you more than anything.
They need their dad.
[Darío sighs]
You can't be the only one that counts.
I'm getting myself a glass
of whatever that is.
It looks too good.
[sighs deeply]
You're not as free as you were before.
[exhales]
[bottles clink]
[Carlos] Um, if you need more space,
we'll use the closet in the hallway.
And if that's not enough,
we'll use the room downstairs.
-It's not Imelda Marcos moving in.
-[Carlos] Who?
The dictator's wife
with the insane amount of shoes.
[Carlos] Oh.
-Has anyone else lived here?
-No, uh, you're the first.
I'm not gonna nurse you back to health
if that's why you wanted me here,
it won't work.
That's not it at all.
I want to live with you.
I'm sure we're gonna do great.
-Oh, yeah?
-Yes.
Because I can cook. I do my own laundry.
I'm organized. I'm good with animals.
[Myriam chuckles]
I want you to feel at home.
And if I don't,
I'll move back to my own condo.
-Don't you worry.
-You're the one that seems worried.
I'm just saying let's try it,
and if it works out,
maybe we start a family--
-Sorry, Carlos.
-Sorry?
Maybe we will? I don't think so.
I'm not ready now,
and if it doesn't happen--
No, no, no. I'm gonna have children.
Whether you're involved or not, I will.
Mm. And if I wanna be involved?
I'm just saying it's not your call.
I'll live my life on my timeline.
Listen, it's like this.
If I decide to have a baby with you,
and it works out, then cool.
But my life is mine to lead. Same as you.
-We stay independent.
-Of course we do.
[sighs] We'll try it.
[phone rings]
[call connects]
-Darío?
-[Darío] A Russian guy got it, man.
-What?
-A Russian guy got the record.
I'm sorry. I'm not following.
A Russian guy fucking jumped
from over 23,000 feet in a wingsuit.
It's all over the web.
[reporter] Valery Rozov set
a new world record
for BASE jumping when he launched himself…
Fuck, he did it from Everest.
…23,688 feet in a wingsuit.
-Whoa.
-[phone rings]
Armando.
…of Mount Everest
took two years of planning.
-Have you seen it yet?
-[Armando] I'm watching it. We're screwed.
[reporter] The sports star from Russia
reached speeds of over 125 miles per hour
before safely landing
on the Rongbuk glacier.
Maybe it's a sign.
The Russian, your divorce.
-Carlos' accident, Chana, Álvaro…
-[sighs]
Our crazy menu.
[rock music playing]
[Darío] A sign of what?
-Huh?
-That there's more to life, I guess.
-[Darío] There's more to life?
-Yes.
Are you trying to depress me?
If we keep forcing and pushing more,
then, pretty soon--
We're not forcing anything.
You gotta trust me.
You cannot compare Everest
to the biggest fucking--
Darío, he jumped in a fucking wingsuit.
Who's gonna sponsor us now?
So, he showed that it can be done.
He got the record.
Good for him. Now people know who he is.
Did he climb Nameless and jump from there?
It doesn't compare.
Christ.
-Carlos says he found options.
-Yeah.
If he says there's options,
then there's options.
-[phone vibrating]
-[Darío] It's gonna happen.
-Sorry.
-[Darío] You're leaving?
Doing a dry run on the menu.
We reopen Friday,
and Juan Manuel's going crazy.
-I'll get the next one.
-[scoffs]
If the option to do Pakistan
doesn't work out,
then I'll settle for Benidorm.
Go taste your menu.
So, what do I owe you?
[laughs]
-[Darío] Is this place a bookstore too?
-[bartender] I bought it.
-Has it changed your life?
-Not yet.
Gotta read the whole thing.
-What's your name?
-Letizia.
With a Z.
Like the queen.
[door opens]
[both laughing]
[both panting]
Where are we goin'?
If you think I'll just follow…
the answer's yes.
-[both laughing]
-Hello, Your Majesty.
[both moaning]
-God damn it, hold on.
-What's wrong?
[sighs]
[tense music rises]
[Darío] It's the Gran Vía.
-[Letizia] Yeah?
-Wow.
-Hello?
-Holy shit.
What are you looking at?
[Darío] Wow.
You live here?
I actually move out tomorrow.
Why are you leavin'?
It was just a sublet,
and I found something half the price
I won't have to share.
-Can I come back in about ten minutes?
-'Kay.
[music fades]
-[door opens, closes]
-[scoffs]
-Sorry, we're not--
-I need to see Armando.
Ah.
-[Armando] I would change the order--
-Have you ever done Plaza de España?
-What are you doing here?
-Thirty-second floor.
-I'm so sorry. Give me a sec.
-Sure.
-My friend.
-Take your time.
-Apologies.
-It's quite all right.
-A balcony looking out on the street.
-[door closes]
-What have you been smoking?
-On a silver platter. We gotta do it.
-Darío, it's two o'clock in the morning.
-So, not too much traffic on the Gran Vía.
[intense flamenco music rises]
-It's too good.
-I'm working.
You tell me you don't wanna go for it,
and I'll leave you alone.
But it's Madrid Tower, 32nd floor.
The view's insane.
The bartender lives there now,
but she leaves tomorrow.
[sighs]
I can't afford to leave here
on bad terms, okay?
-You won't. Nobody's gonna say anything.
-We even brought our cameras.
And you're gonna land there,
in the middle of the street, in the plaza?
-Yes. I'll be back up here right after.
-Mm.
You better, because I want an orgasm.
-[laughs]
-I do owe you.
[sirens wailing in distance]
Told you the view's insane.
-[both laugh]
-[Armando sighs]
[Darío] We jump when the light is green,
open quickly,
and we should be landing
when it turns red.
[intense music rises]
[huffs]
Ready?
Set.
-Go!
-[exclaims]
-[chute whooshes]
-[Darío] Wow! [laughing]
Whoa!
[both exclaiming]
-[sirens wailing]
-[tires squeal]
-[Darío] Is that me?
-[officer] Stay. Do not move!
[Darío] I don't know why I thought
we wouldn't get caught.
-Those cops were pissed!
-[officer] You can't be doing that.
[Carlos] Darío's packing up
in a fucking hurry.
-[Darío] "You can't be doing that."
-No! Do what I asked you.
[Iris] Good thing I didn't have
to bail you out, buster.
[all laughing]
-[Carlos] Back on the horse, huh, buddy?
-I did miss it a little.
-A little?
-[all laugh]
-[officer] You do it again…
-Carlitos.
What's the plan for Pakistan? [laughs]
I'm not sure we're gonna need one.
Between my concussion
and the lack of sponsorship…
[Armando sighs]
How about we plan a trip
to the Maldives to go surfing?
'Cause the Maldives
don't cost an arm and a leg, huh?
[Darío] You guys go on vacation
wherever you want.
But I'm not working like a dog
till all hours not to go flying.
If a sponsor shows up, that's great,
but if not, I don't give a fuck.
Because I'm going to Pakistan.
Even if it's in a tuk-tuk.
Who's with me?
[sighs]
The beast.
[intense flamenco beat playing]
FOUR MONTHS LATER
[tapping continues]
[tapping ends]
[music ends]
[phone ringing]
-Yeah?
-[Armando] Hey, you busy?
Just working on my presentation.
-You gotta talk to Darío.
-What is it?
-He's hell-bent on taking it higher.
-Fuck.
Yeah. He says the festival's
to honor Álvaro,
so he wants to show off a little.
-He's getting on my nerves.
-Put him on.
Carlos wants to talk.
[grunts]
[Darío takes a deep breath]
-What'd this guy tell you?
-Darío, you can't fuck with the altitude.
Who said I was?
If the jump point is set,
you have to respect it, brother.
He's overreacting.
He's on edge. You know how he gets.
-And he's not my teacher.
-Listen to me.
I just need you in shape for Pakistan.
We leave in two months,
so no fucking around.
Really? Two months?
I close the sponsorship deal tomorrow.
Jesus Christ, are you serious?
Yeah, we're good to go,
so stick to the plan.
Fine. You can tell me about it later.
-[chuckles] Yeah.
-Hugs to Myriam.
All right.
-Darío sends hugs.
-[Myriam] Everything okay?
What's that?
Open it.
DR. MARTA SANTOS RUBIO
NOTARY
THIRTY THOUSAND
[Myriam] It's my contribution to the trip.
I don't get it.
I got a bank loan.
You got a loan?
Why are you mad?
I'm not, but this is more than enough
to cover the whole expedition.
I qualified for it, so why not?
It's my money.
I've been busting my ass for months
to line up sponsors,
and the bank gives it to you?
So, you're pissed a bank
is footing the bill?
You should've discussed it with me first.
-I can borrow against my condo.
-You want to impress me or something?
You want me to thank you
for being our savior?
No, I just want you to take the check.
Look, if you feel guilty
because the documentary…
Get over yourself, Carlos!
No one changes anyone, that was the deal.
You're the one who's changed.
No. I haven't.
You're not pitching tomorrow.
There's no meeting.
-I know.
-I know you're lying.
It's a contract for a desk job,
working nine to five.
With a paycheck,
vacation, and a lunch hour.
-Like most people in the fucking country?
-Why did you lie to Armando and Darío?
Why did you hide things from them?
-Because it doesn't matter.
-Sure. They won't think it matters.
Your giving up your climbing lifestyle
won't affect anyone.
And you want to save me
by getting in debt?
Huh? Because I might not make it
with a real job?
-No. Because it isn't you.
-It is.
The hippie's matured.
-You can't mean that. [scoffs]
-I'm serious.
You don't know what I'm thinking
because we fuck,
we live together,
you attend my conferences.
-You're being dramatic.
-I knew it.
-What, exactly?
-That you're a groupie.
I didn't mean it. Wait, Myriam.
-I didn't mean it.
-Well, I do, asshole.
[sighs]
[birds singing]
[somber music playing]
[sighs]
[man on PA speaking indistinctly]
10TH AERIAL JUMP FESTIVAL
[man on PA] You're not gonna miss
a second of this.
And make sure to stop by
the balloon stand with all the kids.
-[Armando] Ready?
-Yes.
You wanna go in the first paramotor?
-Why?
-To be the first one out.
No. Let's stick to what we practiced.
-Darío, are you pissed about the call?
-Why would that piss me off?
I don't like babysitting my friends.
Armando, it's a fucking beautiful day.
We have fans who want a good show.
-That's what's important. Try to enjoy it.
-Be careful.
[dramatic music rises]
[huffs]
[dramatic music continues]
[motors whirring]
[music fades]
Oh, you don't have to.
-Welcome aboard, Carlos.
-Thanks.
-[man speaking on PA]
-[crowd murmuring]
[sighs deeply]
[somber piano music playing]
Come on! Higher.
[tense music rises]
[exhales sharply]
[wind whistling]
Wow! [exclaims]
-[excited chatter]
-[sighs]
[tense music playing]
Okay! Right here.
[crowd exclaims]
[crowd gasps]
[audience clamoring]
[cheering]
[chuckles slightly]
[uneasy silence falls]
[phone ringing]
IRIS
INCOMING CALL
[mournful music playing]
[phone ringing]
Tell me how it went.
I saw there was a record crowd to--
He what?
Oh, how bad?
[mournful music continues]
[sirens wailing in distance]
AMBULANCE
CIVIL GUARD
[somber music playing]
[speaking inaudibly]
[somber music intensifies]
[crying softly]
[somber music fades]
[Armando exhales shakily]
How do we do it?
I'm thinking we put it on the back
of the trunk and blast it off with water.
You sure? Don't we need soap?
[sighs]
Your turn.
We were still pissed when we took off.
[sighs] It's so…
It's so fucked up that's how it ended.
We have to let it settle into place.
[sniffles]
My mom made me promise
I would give it all up.
No more wingsuits.
I can be content
with surfing with Iris or--
Content is not happy.
[huffs]
This isn't the best time
for big decisions.
-I disagree.
-Because?
Do you intend to run after Nameless
until it's finally your turn to die?
[sniffles]
Our turn is our turn.
But I can't keep chasing mine.
[sighs, sniffles]
The other day, somebody sent me a video
of a guy doing a proximity stunt.
[inhales sharply]
He wanted to broadcast his jump live,
so, he put his phone in his pocket,
switched it to audio only, and took off.
-Fuck.
-No image, right? Just the sound.
It's purely the wind
in the first few seconds.
And you can hear it flapping
through his wingsuit like you're there.
Then a panicked reaction.
And a whole lot of… [breathing shakily]
The impact, brutal impact.
But right after, there's complete silence.
You can't hear anything.
Until the fucking cowbells.
[both chuckle sadly]
Cowbells.
The bells and the mooing. Like a concert.
The feeling of peace
at that moment is absolute.
Almost angelic.
It makes you wonder, how that tragedy…
is so easily erased.
And life goes on.
[both chuckle sadly]
-[cows mooing]
-[cowbells ringing]
I called Iris. She was there, right?
The first thing I said was,
"How are you doing?"
And she just cried.
We were both crying our eyes out.
And once we could talk,
I said, "We have two choices."
"Escape to Paris and get lost in paintings
or buy some booze and get wasted."
"Whichever works."
-[interviewer] And what did she choose?
-[chuckles]
So, up and over?
[sighs]
Up and over.
[exhales]
[Iris] Let's go.
[reflective music playing]
[music fades]
[Armando] I was so glad
they went climbing.
They needed it.
It took me a little longer
to go out again.
[interviewer] Did you keep your promise
to your mother?
I didn't put away the wingsuit,
but I gave up the proximity.
I kept up with BASE jumping
and climbing. I had to.
There are certain things in life
that you just can't give up.
[interviewer] And the trip to Pakistan?
-Armando didn't tell you?
-[interviewer] No.
And what about the Corral?
[energetic dance music playing inside]
[excited chatter]
-[Juanma] A toast to all of us.
-[mother] All of us.
-[Iris] You did it.
-[Juanma] No, we did it.
And to my boys, whose father would be
incredibly proud of what you've done.
-[Armando] Here's to Dad.
-We miss you.
-Love you, honey.
-[phone ringing]
-Hm?
-It's Carlos.
Tell him, "Hi."
-Big hugs.
-He's in Pakistan now.
[phone rings, connects]
Hey, brother! Where are you, in Kashmir?
Yeah, I wanted to check in,
'cause I won't be reachable.
Guess what we got.
-The star?
-Yes! [laughs]
Armando! Shit!
-Myriam!
-What?
We have a Michelin star!
-Nice!
-[laughs]
Not only did we get it,
but we're the only tablao to have one.
The only restaurant
with live performance awarded a star,
so get your ass over here
and come try our damn food.
-[Carlos] He's in a good mood.
-He is. We'll toast when you get back.
-Sounds good. See you in a month.
-Have you seen it yet?
I'm lookin' at it right now, my man.
-[crows cawing]
-[Carlos] We gotta get going.
-We'll be back before you know it.
-Yeah, we'll celebrate that too.
Okay, brother.
[sighs]
KARAKORAM, PAKISTAN
[meditative music playing]
DAYS LATER, CARLOS MADE HIS BASE JUMP
FROM NAMELESS TOWER AT 19,685 FEET
HE DEDICATED IT TO DARÍO
Ready. Set. Go!
[shouts]
Whoo!
[Carlos] I know
that when people see this,
they'll still think we're crazy.
What we do can't be understood with logic.
[exclaims]
Whoo-hoo! Oh, yeah!
[group exclaiming]
[both laughing]
-[man] Go!
-[exclaims]
[Armando] Sharing emotions
that rock your core.
[group exclaims]
-[man 1] Whoo!
-[man 2] Hasta luego.
[exclaims, laughs]
[Armando] Your idea of yourself, of life.
[exclaiming]
[laughter echoes]
[Carlos] Maybe it's just an illusion.
Most likely, it is.
But who wants to live without that?
[bittersweet music continues]
IN THE MEMORY OF
[music ends]